てめぇが売ったのか？
How many are there?
ウボォーを！
Around five thousand. And that's a fifth of what they were expecting.
イエスと　とるぜ！ どけ！
No... Apparently, he's been playing games in his room.
話!?　何もねえな！
He's so obsessed with Gungi,
he's been skipping meals. Then what about all this food?
落ち着きなよ これは　予言だから
Should we take it for ourselves?
行動によっては　回避もできるって 団長が言っただろ。
You want to take on the King
and his Royal Guard? Don't make me laugh.
ヒソカ　今週 何があったか説明しろ。
Yeah...
言えない。 あぁん？
Sometimes, you can't see how strong someone
is until you have enough strength yourself.
だが　そこにある １つ目の詩の内容は事実だった
They're monsters. I'll do as they say.
…とだけ言っておこう。 聞いたろ　どけ！ まぁ　待てって。
When Shaia-dono gave us our powers, he'd probably anticipated that
things would turn out this way.
ヒソカ　なぜ　言えない？
Hagya's the only one who doesn't get it!
それを言ったら 言えない内容を言ったも同然。
If you call him by his old name, he gets mad.
ヒソカの占いから
Like the others, he has used
only physical attacks thus far.
彼が裏切り者だと疑った ノブナガが　刀を抜いた
Okay, let me know if he shows his power.
チッ　やめとくぜ。 てめぇは　やりづれぇからな。
Once Welfin and Brovada arrive,
we'll take care of those figures in white. I can also check out the
powers those two have.
ん？ 何!?
Damn, I lost sight of him!
ノブナガ。 少し黙れ。
Leol-sama, it appears that the suit
with glasses is able to teleport.
今の　団長か？ 多分。
Knov's ability is called Hide and Seek.
ヒソカ　いくつか質問する。
Four-Dimensional Apartment Complex
Hide and Seek It allows him to teleport.
答えられないものは 「言えない」でいい。 詩にあった　「攫われた秘密」 というのは　何だ？
By placing a hand against a wall or the ground,
he can open a portal to access Nen space.
団員の能力。 それは　何人だ？
He is able to transport people
and objects through that portal.
７人…　いや　８人か。 団長に　ウボォーギン
Hide and Seek creates a Nen space of
twenty-one rooms, on four floors.
シズク　マチ　フランクリン パクノダ　シャルナークに
Each room is isolated.
僕で　８人だ。 ん？　お前が　コルトピの能力を 知ったのは　昨日か。 その通り。
The entrance shuts when anyone enters, so to return to the real world,
one must exit by a different door.
相手の能力は？ 言えない。
It is possible to create multiple entrances.
相手の　なりかたちは？ 言えない。
The number of possible entrances differs
depending on the size of the room.
お前と相手との関係は？ 言えない。
The exit leads back to the portal used for entry.
なるほど。
So, as a general rule, one can only enter
and exit via the location of the entry portal.
「赤目の客」　鎖野郎は 最低でも２つの能力を有する敵だ。
However, using Knov's master key, an exit can be linked to any portal.
後者の能力は　「掟の剣」という 表現から察するところ
Nothing out of place.
相手に　何らかのルールを 強いるものだろう。
Still quiet on the battlefront.
「俺にウソをつくな」と
Morel's Deep Purple is used for
primarily defensive purposes.
「俺に関する説明を一切するな」 といったところか。
If a puppet encounters someone who
isn't an ally, it will keep its distance.
ここからは　さらに想像によるが ヒソカの体内には
If it comes under attack, it will
retreat, while fighting back.
敵が仕掛けた何かが 埋まっている。
The puppets fight back by throwing
nearby objects at the enemy.
「物々交換」で「差し出す」と あるにもかかわらず 「攫う」のでは 前後の文章が食い違ってしまう。 これは　「掟の剣」が ヒソカを攻撃するという予言を
They avoid direct contact, so the enemy won't realize
they are Nen puppets.
暗示させるため。 つまり　「差し出す」には
That's a Chimera...
「剣で刺す」という意味も 掛けてある。 あぁ…　いいよ
What is it doing? We're pretty far from the battlefield. Is it scouting the area?
ヒソカの言動を規制している剣は かなり強制力の大きな能力だ。
There were strange dragonflies around town.
やっぱり　いいよ　あなたは
I thought they were a local species,
but might they be created from his Nen?
絶対に　あなたは　僕が殺る
It's very likely...
ちょっと　整理してみましょう。 敵は　鎖の使い手。
If it's a Chimera Ant that specializes in
gathering intel, I must neutralize it quickly!
操作系なら　実物の鎖を使って ウボォーを倒した。
The battle is on.
具現化系なら　「念」で作った鎖を 使って　ウボォーを倒した。 それって　何か違いあるの？
Hey... Hey!
大ありさ　具現化系なら 手ぶらを装うことができる。
Aren't you gonna touch me?
これは　大きなメリットだよ。 そっか　具現化系は イメージ修行が大変だけど
Look how close I am... I know you're awake.
一度　具現化ができてしまえば 出し入れ自由だもんね。
Whoa, there!
問題は　それより ヒソカを縛っている力。
I knew you were faking it. You can't trick me!
何かを守らせてんだろ？
With you being so noisy, I can't fall asleep! Give me some peace and quiet!
２つの命令である可能性は高い。
No way!
あとは 鎖野郎への攻撃不可とかね。
I won't let you get any sleep! I'll keep making noise until you chase me!
そして　多分　約束を破ったら死ぬ。 フフフフ　愉快だね
Idiot... If that's what you wanted,
you should have set a rule to force people to keep chasing you.
僕の体内に「掟の剣」なんて 刺さってないのに
Looks like he's still getting
used to his new power...
あの予言は　僕の創作
Have it your way.
能力を話した人数も ８人じゃなく２人
I won't be getting up for the next five hours.
もしも　団長が 僕の暗示に気づかなければ
He's really focused on making
this a contest of speed.
「旅団」全員を敵に回す 危険な賭け 全ては　「クモ」を ヨークシンにとどまらせ
Coupled with his constant need for attention, it's unlikely that he'll settle for
any other type of contest.
団長と戦うため
I'm not gonna let you sleep!
ヨークシンを出れば
Hey! Over here!
いつ　また団長に会えるか 分からないからね
I'm within reach... Get up! Look how close I am.
２つ目のヒソカの予言は どういう意味なのかな？
If he gives up and moves away...
なるほど。 ウボォー　ヒソカ　シズク
9-9-1, marshal.
パクノダ　シャルナーク 半分まで　あと１人。
1-5-1, marshal. 7-9-1, pawn.
他には　死の予言が出た者は いないんだな？
2-3-1, pawn.
じゃあ　俺かフェイタンか コルトピだな。
8-1-1, spy.
俺達　データ不足で 占ってもらえてねえから。 僕は　ここに残るよ。
2-3-1, cannon.
死ぬ前に　まだ やりたいことが　あるんでね。
9-1-1, fortress.
仮宿は離れない。
2-7-2, musketeer. The marshal has been isolated...
団長　どうする？ 引くか　残るか。
I'll call this "remote concealment."
残ろう。
3-2-2, major general.
ダメだ。 えっ　何で？
I'm done.
さっきまで 「幻影旅団」を捕まえるって
Her initial placement was exactly as expected.
ノリノリだったじゃん。 捕まえても 意味なくなったからだよ。
She's shifting toward my marshal
without breaking her crane formation.
だから　何でさ？ 「旅団」に懸けられてた賞金が パになったんだから
Let us begin, then.
残ってんのは　リスクだけだろ？
Her first move will be to position
her archer on her right flank.
そりゃそうだけど 「旅団」を捕まえること自体は
She'll probably try a three-pronged
attack to end it quickly.
無意味じゃないよ！ そういうの 趣旨が変わるっていうんだよ。 俺達が　ここへ来た最初の目的 忘れたのかよ。
But shifting her pieces to the right
exposes her left flank to attack.
『グリードアイランド』。 だろうが！
It's time to disrupt your rhythm.
少しでも金策に走んないで どうすんだ。
1-9-3, new archer.
実はさ　俺　ゲームに関しては 秘策があるんだ。
There it is.
何だよ　秘策って。 ん…。
9-7-1, new spy.
今は　まだ内緒！
2-9-1, knight.
てめぇ　もったいぶらずに言えよ！
Her three-pronged attack
and left flank movement
絞まるって　ホントに絞まってる！
will cost me two pieces.
とにかく　ゲームは俺に任せて
But that created an opening in her left flank.
もう少し「旅団」のほうを 追ってみようよ。 本当に秘策は　あるんだろうな。
She'll probably expect me to
go all-in from that side.
うん　絶対に うまく行くってわけじゃないけど。
But I won't! Here it is!
お前の読みでは　何％ぐらいだ？ え？ その作戦が成功する確率だよ。
5-5-1, lieutenant general.
あ　いや…　やっぱり ６０％ってとこかな。 恐らく　五分五分ってとこか
Each of her moves has followed
a set rhythm until just now, when she froze.
それでも ２日で６０億稼ぐよりか
Given the current placement, I can attack through the
center in unlimited ways.
よっぽど　現実的な数字だな
There is no best move.
よし　分かった ゲームの件は　とりあえず任す。
With every turn, I have the
ability to extend the match.
そのかし　「旅団」のほうは 俺達だけじゃ　絶対無理だ。
Now, let me hear you
クラピカの協力が 絶対必要条件だからな。
squeal!
緋の眼の番も頼むわよ。 ああ　こいつらがいるから 大丈夫だ。
9-2-1, new lieutenant general.
どうだった？ 何とも要領を得ないな。 今日の競売について 聞いてみたが
You knew my strategy was a dead end. Yes. Why did you need to think
before making your move?
コミュニティーの回答は まだだそうだ。
You could have made that move at once.
「旅団」が みんな生きてるってことも 教えてやればいいじゃねえか。
The King has moved this match off the board.
そうすりゃ マフィアも考え直すだろ。
A wrong answer could mean
いや　結果は　恐らく同じだろう。
her death.
コミュニティーは　流星街との摩擦を 懸念しているからな。
Your "remote concealment" strategy
「旅団」への攻撃は 完全に終結したとみていいだろう。
is actually named "kokoriko."
そうか…。 だが　私が本当に知りたいのは そこじゃ　ない。
I came up with that strategy... ten years ago.
競売が　予定通り行われるか どうかの一点だ。
Placing the lieutenant general in the center
お前　まさか　迎え撃つ気か？ そりゃ　いくら何でも無謀だぜ。
to counter a three-pronged attack is also a
move I devised, called "general in the middle."
どうやって　マフィアの援護なしに 戦うつもりだよ。
At the time, both drew a lot of attention.
それは誤解だよ　レオリオ。
Moving from kokoriko to general in the middle
was a popular transition that tested
奴らの後ろ盾など 最初からない。 あっ　あ…。
both players' ability to read their opponents.
クラピカ！　俺達にも 何か手伝わせてよ。
I was pretty happy
何でもいい　どんなことでもやる！ 断れ
that a fool like me could figure
out a smart strategy...
賞金は撤回されたんだぞ？ 分かってる。
But then, I saw how to defeat it.
「旅団」を止めたい その気持は変わってないよ。 断れ　断れ 命懸けだぞ。 おいおい　火に油だっつうの
A year after I came up with kokoriko, an opponent used it against me
in the national tournament, and I figured out how to counter it.
よし　打ち合わせをしよう。 うん！
I won the match, but the strategy disappeared from
official matches and textbooks.
やるんかい！
That the Supreme Leader thought
of the same strategy as I had...
まず　奴らのアジトを張る役 中継係が１人。 俺が　やるよ。 ターゲットは パクノダという女のみ。
I was so honored, and touched...
My heart trembled.
それ以外は　無視していい。 ＯＫ。
It felt like...
大丈夫　無理はしない。 私と共に行動する　運転手が１人。
Like seeing my child brought back to life.
レオリオ　頼めるか？ えっ!?
That was how it felt.
おっ　おう…。 平気だよ　クラピカのそばなら 安全だから。 おい　キルア！ まるで　俺がビビって
So it was difficult for me
to take that life again.
一瞬　間が空いたみたいな とり方すんな！
That was why
クラピカ　俺は？
I hesitated.
また　奴らと直接 対峙しなきゃなんないじゃん。
Foolishness.
それは　やり方次第だ。
I've had enough.
やり方？　どんな作戦だよ。
Get some rest.
敵が　ゴンに 気をとられている隙に 私がパクノダを捕らえ 車で連れ去る。
Once we begin again, you won't get any more breaks.
何だよ　そのアバウトな作戦。
Be prepared!
不確定要素が多過ぎて　これ以上 細かな作戦は立てられない。
Y-Yes...
方法は　ゴンに任せるが 最低０．５秒　できれば１秒 相手の注意を引きつけてほしい。
I believe this is the first time the King has ever listened
to anyone speak for such a long time.
１秒…　だね。 ああ。
Well, it should have no significance...
できるだろうか…
Four hours have passed?
ゴン　お前がカギだ　できそうか？
He got bored and started reading...
まだ分からない　考えてみるよ。
That guy's too easy to understand.
もしも　競売が予定通りなら
Oh, you're ready to start? Has it already been five hours?
それまでに「クモ」は　必ず動く。
Wait, it's only half full.
もちろん 私のリスクが増したからだ。
You just noticed?
早急にパクノダを 始末せねばならない。
We aren't starting now.
何を犠牲にしてもだ。 こいつ…
It's already over. Look at your ankle.
クラピカに感じた 威圧感の正体は　これか
A rope of smoke?
前以上の覚悟
That took a lot of effort...
クラピカ 俺にも「念」の刃を刺してよ。 「『念』の刃を」って…。
I had to go all the way around
so you wouldn't notice, so it turned into quite a long rope.
ゴン　話　聞いてたか？ クラピカは　「旅団」以外の人間を 攻撃したら　死ぬんだぞ！
In any case, all that's left
is to wind up the rope.
声が　デカい！ だったらさ　何でクラピカの胸には 「念」の刃が刺さってんの？
Now it's only a matter of time.
クラピカは 「旅団」の人間じゃないでしょ？
Your turn to try whatever you can.
ここからの話は　さらに 私のリスクを上げることになる。
But it won't work.
ＯＫ。
You should take the smoke seriously.
おい　キルア。
Essentially, it's a rope that can't be severed.
結論から言おう それは　確かに可能だ。
I knew it... He won't attack me because
this is a game of tag.
５つの鎖には　それぞれ 違う能力が宿っている。 その中で 「クモ」攻撃用の鎖は２つ。
If I touch his body, it will break his ability.
１つは「チェーンジェイル」。
He has no patience, but he chose
for the game to last eight hours.
捕らえた者を強制的に 「絶」の状態にして拘束する。
I'm not the one you're putting pressure on.
「クモ」を捕らえるための能力だ。
The pressure's on you.
そして　これが 「ジャッジメントチェーン」。 標的の心臓に　この刃を刺して ルールを宣言し
Cheetu's power was still a work in progress. With his back against the wall,
desperate for a way out...
順守させる。 そのルールを破れば　死。
He created a new ability.
最初は　単純に
A crossbow and claws.
「『クモ』でない者を 鎖で攻撃すれば死ぬ」 …というルールを考え 自分に刃を打とうとした。
He can fight at any range.
だが　その時　ふと思った。
Thanks! You helped me gain an awesome new power!
私自身への攻撃も そのルールの範疇だったら？
Hey, do you know what this is?
私だけは 例外になるのかもしれないが
You sure you want to come closer?! There!
確実に そうだと言える自信は　なかった。
I'm quite sure.
そこで　ルールを限定した。 「チェーンジェイル」での攻撃は 「クモ」にしか使わない。
Why would you want a power
that's slower than you are?
従って　「ジャッジメントチェーン」は 「クモ」以外にも使える。
Ah. Why don't you try those claws?
ただし　使用条件がある。 使用条件？
Then I won't have to walk over. I'll tell you why you lost.
この鎖は 緋の眼の時にしか使えない。
It's because you're an idiot.
中指の能力は 手元から離さないことと
Die! Then you can never touch me!
死というリスクを背負うことで クリアした。
This sensation...
小指のほうは 私の特異体質が解決してくれた。
It can't be... Smoke?
緋の眼が現れた時 私は　特質系となり
No way!
覚えた能力であれば
Caught you.
１００％の精度　威力で 使用できる。
Wh-When did you...
よく　分かんないけど つまり　「念」の刃は 俺にも刺せるってことだよね？
While you were reading manga
and laughing like a fool, I created a copy of myself from smoke.
ああ。
And I covered myself with smoke
that looked like grass.
いいよ　ルールは任せる。
My copy went one way, and I went the other.
お前の覚悟　確かに受け取った。 その刃ってさ　３本　出せる？
The fight continues, even while one sleeps. You shouldn't have looked away.
任務完了の後は そのルール　解除できるんだろうな？
Looks like we're back...
キルア　レオリオ！
Well, do you still want to fight?
こっちも　２人で話したんだが やっぱり　参加するからには…。
No, I've had enough.
一連托生っしょ。
That's a wise decision...
答えは？
Then why not tell me
両方とも可能だ。
what would have happened
if I hadn't caught you?
だが　３人とも １つ勘違いしている。
There's no point in asking.
私は　お前達に刃を刺す気など
Once I've been caught,
I can't use that power anymore.
初めから　全くないのだよ。
That was the condition I set.
だったら 何で　リスクが増すだけなのに こんな話を…。
Really? I feel bad...
ゴン　お前の… いや　お前達の覚悟に対する
It's no big deal. I'll ask Shaia-sama for a new power!
私なりの礼だよ。
Next time, I won't lose.
仮に　お前達から 秘密が漏れたとしても
You'd better be ready! His superior
私は　もう　何ひとつ後悔しない。
is most likely a Royal Guard named Shaia, who has the power to release Nen skills.
私は　いい仲間を持った。
So if the selection is carried out,
winning will become very difficult.
ずるいよ　クラピカ。
Gon and Killua made the right choice.
そんなこと言われたら 命　懸けるより
We need to meet. Let's talk inside.
よっぽど　プレッシャーに なっちゃうよ。
Reinforcements have arrived.
それが　狙いだからな。
It's a crayfish and a wolf.
なんだ　そうか　アハハ…！
Are they strong? If I knew, my job would be easier...
フフフフ…。 笑えねえぞ　おい
Right now, they're trying to gauge our strength. So it's currently a stalemate.
おっ　さて… んじゃ　俺　行くよ。
Our goal is to buy time, so it all works out.
時間が　もったいないからね。
I suspect it's because I took out this one.
キルア　気をつけてね。 おう　任しとけって。
Those dragonflies were acting
as security cameras.
それじゃあ　班を決める。
borrow an ability in exchange
for granting the target a favor.
来週は　この班を基本に動き 単独行動は　絶対に避けること。
However, two conditions must be met.
シズク　パクノダ　マチ。
First, he must have seen the ability or know its name.
コルトピ　フィンクス　フェイタン。
Second, he must grant a favor.
ノブナガとシャルナークは　俺と。 ボノレノフ　フランクリン ヒソカは　ここで待機。
After confirming that his favor is not
free and is expected to be repaid, this skill will activate, assuming
the target agrees to his conditions.
団長　１つ　いい？ 子供がさ ここの場所　知ってんだけど。 子供？ まぁ　鎖野郎とは 関係ないみたいなんだけど
Got it! Once all conditions are met, Leol's
dispenser automatically stores data, which can be checked at any time.
やっぱり　どうも　気になるのよね。 そうだ　忘れてたぜ！ 団長　そいつの入団　推薦するぜ！
However, if the target dies,
the data will be deleted. Flutter's fine.
ちょっと… こっちは　そんなつもりで 話をしてんじゃないよ。
I believe there's been no communication
話してくれ。
because he's unconscious or far away.
なるほど 確かに面白そうな奴ではある。
A rental can be used for one hour. During the rental period, the target
cannot use the borrowed power.
が　話を聞く限り　そいつは 「クモ」には　入らないだろう？
Anyway, Flutter is still alive...
説得するさ！ とにかく　一度　見てくれ。
Looks like we'll be able to stay in touch. Once Flutter's Satellite Dragonflies
団長　ダメだよ 乗せられちゃ。
verify the location of the suit
with the glasses, we'll start.
で　マチ お前が　気になることとは？ え？　あ　何となく。
So we keep the small fry at a distance
while you take on the suit with the glasses. You gonna be okay on your own?
勘か？ お前の勘は　頼りになるからな。 その子供　もしかしたら　何か
Just trust me. I wouldn't give
you a job you can't handle.
重大な　つながりが あるかもしれない。
And I don't want you to see my power.
用心のため　アジトのダミーを 増やしておくか。
I'll do whatever it takes to
complete this mission.
コルトピ　あと１０棟　行けるか？
Okay...
５０は平気。 それと　偽のアジトに 誰かが侵入すれば　すぐ分かるよ。
I can't afford to wait around here. Not until the King is in my debt!
僕のコピー 「円」の役割も果たすから。
When Leol takes the dispensed IOU and
tears it up, the effect activates.
ん!?
They're here.
何かが違う…　場所？
Time to start scouting.
あっ　まさか…
I don't understand.
アジトの建物が増えてる！
This is upsetting. During our matches, I am the only
one who's getting flustered.
降りしきる雨の中
I would have expected this to be
humiliating on a new level. But...
パクノダを捕らえる作戦が 始まった
At the same time, I am enjoying our matches.